Finding Aid for Freemasons, Fraternity Lodge, No. 262 F.&A.M. (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records, 1869-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Freemasons, Fraternity Lodge, No. 262 F.&A.M. (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records 1869-2003
Freemasons. Fraternity Lodge No. 262 F. & A.M. (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
2010066 Bd 2
Masonic lodge founded in 1869 in Ann Arbor, Michigan; minutes, membership records, and other administrative materials.
7 linear feet
24 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated in 2009 by Ann Arbor Fraternity Lodge, No. 262 (donor number 7821 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Fraternity Lodge, No. 262 was formed in Ann Arbor, Michigan in 1869. Three other Masonic bodies, Ann Arbor Lodge No. 85, Golden Rule Lodge No. 159, and Washtenaw Chapter No. 6, emerged in the Ann Arbor area prior to the Fraternity Lodge. Throughout the years, the Fraternity Lodge has shared the Masonic Temple with the other Ann Arbor area Masonic bodies.
The records of the Fraternity Lodge, No. 262 cover the period between 1869 and 2003. The record group consists primarily of minutes, correspondence, financial records, rulebooks, membership records, petitions, and questionnaires. The records are arranged into three series: Meeting Minutes, Administrative, and Membership.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Freemasons. Fraternity Lodge No. 262 F. & A.M. (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Freemasons--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Freemasonry--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Meeting Minutes
  Meeting Minutes series contains the minutes of Fraternity Lodge's monthly meetings.
  - 1891-1900 (Volume 1)
  - 1900-1908 (Volume 2)
  - 1908-1914 (Volume 3)
  - 1914-1915 (Volume 4)
  - 1915-1919 (Volume 5)
  - 1919-1923 (Volume 6)
  - 1924-1928 (Volume 7)
  - 1929-1933 (Volume 8)
  - 1934-1940 (Volume 9)
  - 1940-1944 (Volume 10)
  - 1944-1953 (Volume 11)
  - 1954-1966 (Volume 12)
  - 1959-1978 (Volume 13)
  - 1975-1979 (Volume 14)
  - 1954-1955 1967-2000, 30 folders (Box 1)
    (formerly bound volumes, some gaps)
- Administrative
  Administrative series consists of a variety of Fraternity Lodge files including financial material like annual reports and returns, a listing of the Lodge committees, correspondence, by-laws and procedural guidelines.
  - Acacia Lodges 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Binder I 1975-1976, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Administrative Binder II 1969-1977, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Annual Calendar 1977, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports and Finances 1920s-2000s, 10 folders (Box 2)
  - Annual Returns 1940s-1980s, 2000s, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - By-laws 1923, 1953, 1954, 1975, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Centennial History Publication 1970 (Box 2)
  - Committee Listings 1952-1953 (Box 2)
  - Communications
    - 1883, 1886 (Box 2)
    - 1922-1923, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - 1924-1959, 24 folders (Box 3)
      (some gaps)
    - 1960-2000s, 18 folders (Box 4)
  - Consolidation Correspondence 1981-1982, 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Dexter Masonic Property 1997 (Box 4)
  - Festive Board 1991 (Box 4)
  - Grand Lodge Records 1987-2000, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Installation of Officers 1950-1999, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Masonic Foundation 1998 (Box 4)
  - Masonic Letters 1920 (arranged alphabetically), 8 folders (Box 5)
  - Masonic Letters 1921 (arranged alphabetically), 12 folders (Box 5)
  - Michigan Masonic Home 1987-1990 (Box 5)
  - Southeastern Michigan Masonic Board of Relief 1991 (Box 5)
  - Trial for Non-Payment of Dues undated (Box 5)
- Membership
  Membership series documents the associations and activities of the Fraternity Lodge's various members. The series includes membership petitions, which consist of petitions for admissions, change of membership, transfer or demit, and charges for non-payment of dues. The membership record files also contain membership petitions, but instead of being arranged chronologically like the membership petitions, they were arranged by the member's last name. The series also includes membership ledgers, which were used to document payment of dues by each member. Additionally, the series contains material related to the different degrees in Masonry such as ritual scripts and lectures on the history of the Master Mason degree.
  - Application for Pre-Paid Membership Binder 1999 (Box 5)
  - Procedure for Transferring Membership undated (Box 5)
  - Dusty Square and Compasses Degree 1987 (Box 5)
  - Master Mason Degree 1966-1996, 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Mason of the Year 1987-1991 (Box 5)
  - Life Membership Night 1964-1998 (Box 5)
  - Annual Memorial Service 1930s-1990s, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Lodge Memorial Service 1999 (Box 5)
  - Past Masters Annual Recognition Dinner 1954-1992, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Michigan Masonic Membership Master Proof 1993 (Box 6)
  - Membership Lists and Ledger 1920s-2000s, 16 folders (Box 6)
  - Membership Questionnaire 1923 (Box 6)
  - Membership Petitions
    - 1920s-1950s, 13 folders (Box 6)
    - 1960s-2000s, 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Fraternity Lodge records (Box 7)
  - Membership Record Files (arranged alphabetically), 29 folders (Box 7)
  - Bound records
    - Membership, A-Z 1900s-1930s (Volume 15)
    - Membership, La-Z 1900s-1930s (Volume 16)
      (A-K volume not received)
    - Membership, A-Z 1940s-1960s (Volume 17)
    - Withdrawals, Demits, Deaths, etc. 1939 (Volume 18)
    - Investigating Committee Book 1869-1896 (Volume 19)
    - Register of Members and Visitors
      - 1875-1907 (Volume 20)
      - 1941-1958 (Volume 21)
      - 1944-1958 (Volume 22)
      - 1958-1975 (Volume 23)
      - 1975-1980 (Volume 24)